Matthew Charles Bendel II

5 E Northwood Ave. Apt B Columbus, OH 43201 * (330) 607-5113 * bendel.8@buckeyemail.osu.edu GitHub: https://github.com/matt-bendel * Personal Website: http://mattbendel.com

EMPLOYMENT OBJECTIVE

Logical and creative engineer with a desire to be a lifelong learner. Majoring in Electrical and Computer Engineering, with a minor in Mathematics, I seek to find creative solutions to complex problems and to continue gaining experience in a professional engineering environment.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving
- Working in a team environment

- Communication
- Solid understanding of engineering/design principles

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

OHIO STATE ELECTROSCIENCE LABORATORY, Columbus, OH

Student Researcher, Jan 2020 – Present

- Developed an app using the Unity game engine which interfaces with an EEG headset in order to analyze signals
- Created a Django web app with PostgreSQL database to store signals recovered from Unity app

BLUBRRY SOFTWARE, Columbus, OH

Software Developer Intern, May 2020 – August 2020

- Worked using an AMP stack in an agile team using Bitbucket
- Overhauled Blubrry's publisher system, including the onboarding process and their private internal podcasting dashboard
- Wrote use cases for the Blubrry API in Ruby, Python, Node.js, C#, and PHP
- Implemented a WordPress plugin for Blubrry's site to handle support tickets

TOP ECHELON SOFTWARE LLC, Canton, OH

Software Engineering Intern, May 2019 – August 2019

- Worked in a team using the Agile development process
- Gained experience using Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, and HTML
- Gained experience querying databases using SQL
- Gained experience with version control through GitHub
- Implemented a brand new feature from scratch with another intern, as well as updates to several other features

EDUCATION

THE OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY, Columbus, OH

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, Expected: May 2021

- GPA: 3.817/4.0
- Senior standing
- Received Dean's List 6 semesters

ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Extensive experience in a team-based development environment, specifically with agile(scrum)
- Experience developing in Windows and Linux environments
- Experience developing and using RESTful APIs
- Extensive web app development experience in a variety of frameworks (Django, Rails, Laravel)
- Extensive experience ReactJS, jQuery, and Angular and some experience Vue.js with various front-end frameworks, as well as CSS, and CSS3
- Extensive experience working with MySQL databases, and experience working with PostgreSQL
- Excellent at learning and applying new ideas and technologies quickly
- Excellent communication skills
- Excellent diagnostic and problem-solving abilities
- Extensive experience and comfort with version control systems (GitHub and Bitbucket)